

Submitted to Amentum for ARPA-H STATS

NAME	JOB TITLE	PWS Tasks
Bethanne Poindexter	ITDI - Basic Action Officer	7.3.1, 7.3.6, 7.3.5

Job Responsibility	Qualifying Skills
Administrative & Executive Support: Provide office leadership with high-level administrative support, including task tracking and process coordination.	 Served as a Program Management Office (PMO) Analyst at NIH, developing administrative processes, managing SharePoint systems, and assisting with policy documentation. Provided high-level administrative support at Deloitte Federal for NIH, streamlining office operations and implementing workflow improvements. Managed purchase request processing and compliance monitoring for USMC and the Department of the Navy, supporting procurement and contract operations.
Task & Deliverable Management: Track, manage, and ensure the completion of action items, including taskers, briefs, and other deliverables.	 Tracked, managed, and validated IT portfolio applications in DoD IT repositories, ensuring compliance with Marine Corps and Navy requirements. Developed and maintained project tracking systems for NIH's Office of Administration, aligning task execution with leadership priorities. Monitored and ensured compliance with purchase card usage at US Coast Guard, identifying and investigating non-compliant transactions.
Stakeholder Communication & Coordination: Collaborate with internal and external stakeholders to facilitate communication, reporting, and operational efficiency.	 Liaised with federal executives, program managers, and cybersecurity teams at DEA and DOJ, ensuring effective communication and coordination of IT and privacy initiatives. Supported project planning and coordination between federal agencies, including the Department of State, FINCEN, and USMC, optimizing workflow efficiency. Assisted in policy planning and guidance for compliance with DoD and federal regulations, ensuring alignment with executive priorities.

Education

Spelman College, Atlanta, Georgia

Bachelor of Arts, Political Science with a concentration in International Relations

George Mason University, Fairfax, VA

Masters of Science, Institute for Conflict Analysis and Resolution

Boston College, Boston, Massachusetts

Certificate: Program Management for Project Management Professional

United States Congress, Washington, DC

U. S. Congressional Internship

United States Navy, San Diego, CA, Jacksonville, FL and Operation Desert Storm

NEC: Hospital Corpsman/Surgical Technician

May 1995



Experience

Program Analyst II- Purchase Card Program Solutions Through Innovative Technologies, Inc. (dba STI Technologies, Inc.) US Coast Guard, Washington, DC

03/2024 - Present

- Determine compliance with regulations and adequacy in meeting the needs within the Homeland Security/ US
 Coast Guard Purchase Card Programs.
- · Prepare custom reports for the as required, monitors reports and extracts data via already developed reports using the electronic access system.
- Conduct monthly reviews of cardholder accounts within the commercial banking system to ensure the cardholders
 use the card program appropriately within the guidelines established and segregation of usage ability based upon
 role is maintained.
- Researches and investigates new or improved business and management practices for application to the Purchase Card Program.

Information Technology Process Consultant- Privacy NTT Data/Summit-Tek Drug Enforcement Agency Arlington, VA

6/2022 - 1/3/2024

- Works with the Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA) and Department of Justice (DOJ) Legal and Cybersecurity
 partners via components: DOJ Office of Privacy and Civil Liberties and the DEA Office of Chief Counsel) and
 DEA Cybersecurity Program Offices, Information Security System Officers (ISSOs) and other customers to
 assess the IT system's PII identification and Privacy.
- · Provide support to Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA) System Owners and Program Management Offices to complete an Initial Privacy Assessment (IPA), Privacy Impact Assessment (PIA), or any other documentation required to satisfy the agency's Cybersecurity and Privacy compliance requirements.
- · Provide customer service representative of the DEA standard to provide accurate information and/ or assistance to resolve client problems, or satisfy their expectations.
- · Review IPA and PIA documents to ensure that the System Owner (SO) and Program Management Office (PMO) develops and maintains security and procedures to safeguard
- · Personal Identifiable Information (PII) stored within their operating systems.
- · Track all Initial Privacy Assessments (IPAs) and Privacy Impact Assessments (PIAs) that are being developed and have been approved.
- · Provide on-going support of the privacy documentation status sheet in order to track status.
- · Prepare meeting materials such as but not limited to, agenda's, meeting minutes, action items, copies of the Privacy POA&M's and any reports to be used during the discussion.
- · Provide support to PMO and SO throughout the year by tracking and maintaining POA&Ms as it pertains to privacy controls and the development of the Privacy Risk Certificate Memorandum.
- · Utilize the Department of Justice Certification and Assessment Management (JCAM) tool, that the agency uses to track POA&Ms and cybersecurity artifacts.
- · Provide technical support to include technical advice on security requirements for highly specialized application(s), technical report preparation, or other ad hoc services as required.
- Design, prepare and deliver IT security related presentations; review and provide written comments on IT security related artifacts to include but not limited to: IT Security directives, policies, guidelines, plans, and procedures; briefings in response to internal and external cybersecurity data calls; change control management boards and other IT security related requests.



Program Management Office Analyst Deloitte Federal via eTeams Bethesda, MD

11/2021 - 6/2022

- · Supports the implementation of best practices for scalable National Institute for Health (NIH) Information Technology Program management Office (PMO) to include project intake and management processes, resources, training, and a governance plan for sustainment.
- · Performs the development of new PMO templates, artifacts, and communications plans.
- · Develops and manages SharePoint system, site development, database enhancement, in
- · support of the NIH Office of Administration.
- · Assist in the delivery of PMO training to stakeholders ensure their timely socialization.
- · Provides policy planning, guidance, review and update to the manuals under the purview of the NIH Program office of Administration.
- Makes clear and convincing oral presentations; listens to others, attends to nonverbal cues from customers, and responds appropriately and responsibly.

Engagement Manager- ServiceNow ECS Federal for Department of State Washington, DC

9/2021 - 11/2021

- Manages the information technology team on a 3 month project extended for Department of Commerce using the ELITE methodology for the implementation, testing of ServiceNow ITSM modules: Incident Management, Problem Management, Change Management, Configuration Management (CMDB), Service Catalog/Request Management and Service Portal applications.
- Ensure that the business requirement for the Service Catalog supports the proper recording of property and equipment placed in service as part of the asset forfeiture program.

Logistic IT Portfolio Task Lead

3/2020 - 9/2021

Solutions Through Innovative Technologies, Inc. (dba STI Technologies, Inc.) US Marine Corps, Pentagon

- · Supports the USMC Deputy Commandant for Installations and Logistic- LPI assigned to the LP branch by providing analytical and technical expertise for the Logistics IT Portfolio Management (LOGITPfM).
- Monitors and validates LPI portfolio IT applications and systems tracked in the DoD Information Technology Portfolio Repository - Department of the Navy (DITPR DON) and the Department of the Navy. Application and Database Management System (DADMS) from FAMs: PfM SES,LCES, LI2S, LOGCOM, SYSCOM.
- Review and provide analyses to develop Logistics Information Technology (IT) Strategies and other related IT strategic documents. Provides recommendations to and assists the LOG FAM with a review of IT spending requests within their area of responsibility.
- · Align and distribute IT investment reporting requirements and mandates for the development of DC I&L investment, Sustainment and Divestiture Policy to LPI Logistic IT Portfolio.
- Creates the Purchase Requests for USMC I&L, Logistics Division to include OPBUD transfers, Travel Orders, Amendments, Modifications, Basic Contracts for Procurement within PR Builder which feeds into SABRS.
 Maintains the I & L Marine Corps Contracting Program Accounts via Financial Management Tracking(FMT) system.
- · Provides policy planning, guidance, review and update to the manuals under the purview of the Marine and United States Navy office of Administration.
- · Implementing security framework for cyber applications or information technology device upgrades for legacy systems and new implementations.
- · Supports high level projects within the Marine Office of Administration, such as major renovations, and systems, development and enhancement.
- · Supports the proper recording of property and equipment placed in service as part of the asset forfeiture program within the Department of the Navy. Application and Database Management System (DADMS).
- · Assists and monitors the contractor that develops and manages SharePoint system, site development, database enhancement, in support of the Office of Administration.



- · Monitors the implementing security framework for cyber applications or information technology device upgrades in the IT portfolio.
- Ensure establishing routines to analyze and investigate the integrity of data and information within systems during ATO process, continuous monitoring of systems under conditional authority to operate (ATOs).

Deputy Program Manager- ServiceNow NetImpact Strategies Inc. for Department of State and FINCEN

7/2019 - 11/2019

- Facilitates business requirement workgroups for the development of ServiceNow applications with Product Owners, developer/architect and stakeholders between Department of State (DOS) Bureaus and Federal Crimes Enforcement Network (FINCEN).
- · Assist the Product Owner with application backlog grooming and determination of criteria to formulate MVP(Minimally Viable Product).
- · Schedule and monitor Sprints and Retrospectives with Product Owners to examine corrective actions and document accuracy in capture of requirements, application agile development and functionality.
- · Worked with Developers to establish and maintain Release Management schedule for deployment and Operations and Maintenance technical updates.
- · Documented and edited training material associated with applications and systems interchange.
- · Experience managing system, software and application implementations within the federal government space.
- · Organize, direct and coordinate the planning and production of all activities associated with assigned projects.
- · Responsible for planning, establishing, and implementing resources to ensure successful completion of each project and its goals.

IT PMO Governance Enterprise Architecture Lead Superlative Technologies Army National Guard Arlington, VA

10/2017 - 7/2019

- Develop of strategic communication plan with National Guard Bureau G-6 to garner contributions from multiple
 Department of Defense stakeholders and vendors involved in the Enterprise transformation to include enterprise
 directives, training, enterprise technical initiatives cut-overs with end users, functionality testing, functionality
 interruptions, technical subject matter expert workgroups, weekly status with PMO and CIO meetings, Town Hall
 meetings, data call surveys and change management communiques to align with IT strategic objectives, business
 goals, and internal or external compliance needs.
- Partner with the Joint Department of Defense, Army National Guard and Army Chief Information Officers and their staff to ensure the right mix of initiatives align with IT strategic objectives, business goals, and internal or external compliance needs.
- Drive the adoption of Lean and Agile PMO tools, processes, and methodologies to accelerate the planning, oversight, and execution of IT initiatives.
- Assist in the transformation and fostering to operationalize technical governance frameworks, including Cloud, data, or DevOps governance models among ARNG divisions. Conduct IT strategy and governance assessments to include Federal Information Security Modernization Act (FISMA), Privacy Impact Assessments (PIA), Department of Defense Architecture Framework (DODAF), Business Enterprise Architecture (BEA) and Risk Management Framework (RMF).
- · Recommend solutions for improving oversight and decisions—making to drive IT initiatives.
- Establish IT portfolio frameworks and views to create systematic analyses of assets, services, and capabilities based on leadership priorities.
- Develops and maintains security practices as steward of a DOD IT Portfolio and ensures procedures to safeguard Personal Identifiable Information (PII) stored within operating systems especially demonstrated on enterprise architecture logical data flow diagrams (DFD) and physical data flow diagrams are accurate and documented in all applicable systems.
- Provides policy planning, guidance, review and updates to the manuals under the purview of the ARNG Office of Administration.



· Implementing security framework for cyber applications or information technology device upgrades for legacy systems and new implementations.

Portfolio Queue Manager, Creative Business Solutions, Inc. Veterans Administration Washington, DC

5/ 2017 - 10/2017

- Supervise staff of forty- four (44) full-time employees consisting of: Team Leads, Case Analysts and Senior Case Analysts for the delegation of tasks, review and edit work product, administer performance evaluations and manage schedules.
- · Conduct day-to- day office planning, formulate short and long term range professional development plans, perform dispute resolution, draft and enforce disciplinary proceedings.
- Coordinate risk assessment activities; develop and implement long and short-term risk reduction strategy; monitor progress and periodically report to executive management.
- · Responsible for tracking and updating all Veteran Business certification deliverables continuously throughout internal/external projects and delivering feedback to team members.
- · Develops staff training and delivery of all material/training sessions to staff members.
- · Monitors and presents reports defining team progress, issues, and solutions; develop organizational training materials and present to all staff.

IT Program Analyst, 22nd Century Technologies Inc. Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA) Fort Meade, MD

11/2016 - 4/2017

- Ability to collaborate with multiple stakeholders include government executives, developers, business/functional
 users, subject matter expert in the following projects: vetting and obtaining policy for the Risk Management
 Framework security controls for the DISA Integrated Resource Information System (IRIS) application and
 obtaining ATO (authority to operate) for the application and migration of the IRIS pre-production and
 development environments to the Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) platform MilCloud.
- Understand business needs, user requirements and serve as the conduit between the customer community and the software development team. Support several project management support tasks in parallel Understands application functionality, work closely with technical SMEs.

Project Contract Manager, The Ravens Group Bethesda, MD/ Camp Lejeune, NC/Harlingen, TX

7/2015 - 11/2016

- Manages 5 federal contracts for The National Institute of Health, Joint Warfare Analysis Center, Camp Lejeune Dental Corps and The Veterans Administration- Harlingen, TX and Washington, DC
- · Acts as the contractual liaison and point of contact responsible for the development, collection and maintenance of contractual project assessments.
- · Monitors and reviews CPARS system for past performance evaluations on program management contracts.
- · Coordinates and monitors budgets, budget plans and contract thresholds for monthly contract budget with corporate office and project contract officers.
- · Develops and implements recommendations to resolve problems, mitigate or eliminate potential risks and maintain the deliverables schedule.
- · Prepares workload and manpower analyses for the Project Management Team monthly reports to corporate.
- Develops and manages project schedules, risks and issues, lessons learned and deliverables in accordance to program and project management standards (PMI).
- · Monitors and ensures contractual transaction compliance (milestones, deliverables, invoicing etc.)
- · Tracks and maintains issues, risks and deliverable logs for on-going projects.
- · Initiates the implementation work-plans based upon the program management planning scheme.



IT Project Management Analyst, IBM at WALGREENS- Boots Alliance, Lincolnshire, IL 9/2012 - 9/2014

- Prepared and presented IBM Enterprise Technical and Management report decks to Senior Executive Management, Project Enterprise Technical Architects and other cross functional workgroups about the status of the Offshore Transition.
- · Worked closely with the Offshore IBM Service Delivery Managers and the Onshore Walgreens Service Delivery Managers to liaison with technical teams and enterprise management for PMO project status.
- · Utilized program analysis methodologies and techniques to extrapolate data for PMO Transition reports from Remedy, Atlassian and Tivoli monitoring.
- Managed program and technical management deliverables based upon service level agreements/ service level objectives for 10 IBM architecture technical Sub-Tower leaders, within Integration Architecture, Site Architecture and Enterprise Monitoring Services for the Walgreens Enterprise Shared Services Transformation project (ESST).
- · Provided and compiled written qualitative and statistical data reports based upon the quantitative outputs from Remedy and Atlassian for weekly PMO enterprise and technical meetings.
- · Identified analyses issues and inconsistencies in all PMO reporting streams as it pertains to bugs, helpdesk (SLAs) and technical status of the enterprise technical transition.
- Developed and monitored staff augmentation for multiple work streams pertaining to IBM subcontractor team members and Walgreens SMEs, both onshore (CONUS) and offshore (India) for offshore transition of Walgreens' information technology program.

Security Clearance: Secret (Department of Defense)

Certified Product SCRUM Owner (CSPO)